

# **Eduardo Guadalupe Romero Quiñonez**

Full-Stack Web Developer

México City, México (GTM-6) (+52) 722 613 7378

<u>eduardo.gromeroq@gmail.com</u> <u>https://linkedin.com/in/eduardo-grquinonez/</u> <u>https://github.com/eduardogrq</u>

Full-Stack web developer with 4+ years of experience in designing, building, and maintaining web applications with ReactJs, Laravel, Javascript, Node js and AWS cloud services. I have experience with version control tools such as Bitbucket, Github, and Gitlab and working with both relational and non-relational databases for scalability. I have the ability to work independently and in a team to achieve project goals. I am constantly working with React and AWS and would like to continue developing my skills in these technologies, whether remotely or hybrid.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Grupo Siayec, Full-Stack Web developer Semi Sr.** — September, 2022 - Present.

- Reduced incident resolution time by 35% compared to the previous development team by creating precise user stories for better solution development.
- Advanced 87% at the start of the quarter in pending tasks from the previous period through task allocation optimization targeting precise development points.
- I Improved platform maintenance and scalability through the implementation of cloud services solutions (AWS).
- Improvements in solutions to problems identified in the backlog by creating user stories.

Technology stack: React js, Javascript, AWS Services (LAMBDA, GraphQL, Amplify, DynamoDB, Cognito)

## **Smartbis, Full-Stack Web developer.** — June, 2021 - September, 2022

- I Improved data visualization and structure through the design of a functional flowchart.
- I Established a structure for working with components that allow for scalable and functional code.
- I Improved delivery times through task assignment to team members based on the SCRUM methodology.
- I Developed modules for correct management of users, assets, and company organization, based on technologies used at the time (Laravel, React js, Alpine js, Livewire, etc.) which allowed for proper data management on the platform.

**Technology stack**: React js, Javascript, Laravel, Livewire, SQL, Scrum.

### Kodemia, Front-end Web developer. — June, 2020 - June, 2021

- Reduced incident resolution time by 30%.
- Improved the experience of both the user and the administrator on the web platform through the proposal of new features (UX/UI design).
- Developed modules for displaying and modifying users in the administrator section, which allowed for proper data management on the platform.

**Technology stack**: React js, Javascript, CSS, SASS, HTML, Material UI, Scrum.

## Jurídico Melgoza y Asociados, Full-Stack Web developer. — May, 2019 - January, 2021

- I successfully completed the company's main project, meeting all designated requirements. I conducted thorough testing to ensure quality and optimal performance of the website.
- I improved usability and user experience through the use of web design tools.
- I created a fast, efficient, and optimized for conversion website through deep analysis of user needs to design a landing page that offered a smooth experience.
- I improved control over the data entered on the platform by developing modules for proper management of users and programs offered by the company using the technologies used.

**Technology stack:** Javascript, CSS, SASS, HTML, JQuery, MySQL, Laravel.

### **SKILLS**

**Programming languages:** *Advanced*: Javascript; *Intermediate*: PHP; *Basic*: Python

**Frameworks:** *Advanced*: Laravel, React js, Tailwind, Bootstrap; *Intermediate*: AWS Cloud Services (Lambda, DynamoDB, Amplify, Glu), Tailwind, Material UI, Eloquent, GIT, Bash, Node js; *Basic*: Vue js.

**Databases:** *Advanced*: MySQL; *Intermedio*: MongoDB, DynamoDB.

**Tools:** Git, Jira, Slack, Notion, Gitlab, Github, Bitbucket.

Agile: SCRUM

Languages: Intermediate: english; Native: spanish.

## **EDUCATION**

**UTEL Universidad –** *México city, México. Computer Systems Engineering, 2015 - 2019 (Degree).* 

Universidad Autónoma del Estado de México - Toluca, México. Administration Computer Science Bachelor, 2011 - 2013 (4

semesters).

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Bootcamp Full-stack developer (MERN) - Kodemia. 2021. Cloud fundamentals (Azure, GCP, AWS) - Código facilito – 2021. AWS Cloud Practitioner - Amazon – 2023.